Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe in a simple concept: if it's a piece of engineering, it is also a work of art. Also, an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, unlike any other media.



angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



Assam, India



(O) https://www.instagram.com/binaryvectorjr/

7896003410

https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)

Vellore Institute of Technology 2015 - Present Current CGPA - 8.68

High School and Senior School

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School 2003 - 2015

Guwahati, Assam

- Passed 10th standard with 9.4 CGPA
- Passed 12th standard with 93.4%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee

Bharati Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India Achievements/Tasks

- Automated data collection and organization process for SACFA Applicants (using Visual Basic for Applications) which reduced the time for data organization significantly.
- Worked on collecting the azimuth data for various sites for towers using their latitude and longitude.
- Worked on "Project Junoon" by daily updating new sites on the maps, filtering out the sites with maximum problems, and categorizing the different sites.

Graphic Designer

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - Present

Shillong, India

An organization that caters to services such as Event Management, Talent Management, PR, Photography, as well as hosting various events around India

Achievements/Tasks

• Designed the logos for the event "Street Sangam".

ACHIEVEMENTS

Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 – 05/2017)

Led the design department and oversaw various design requirements of the club (BEAM VIT).

Design Co-Chair (BIDSF'17) (01/2017 - 04/2017)

BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT with the help of various clubs. I was responsible for creating the theme, logo, posters and oversee various other design related issues for the event.

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 – 06/2018)

Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT. I was asked to help them out with their design team by organizing their workflow, as well as teaching the members about graphic design. I also helped design their brochures.

SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine SketchUp Autodesk 3DS Max C++ HTML and CSS (W3 CSS) MATI AB Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel) Computer Hardware Knowledge Computer Software Knowledge General Troubleshooting

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- The main purpose of the project was to construct a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- It gives a counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, in order that they don't spill their food.
- Machine Learning is used to detect any anomalies in the sensor data from the device. If an anomaly is detected the device send a mail alert to the wellwishers of the patient.

Automated Medicine Dispenser (12/2017 – 04/2018)

- The goal was to make people of any age (especially the old people) suffering from memory lapses, remember all the medicines they have to take throughout the day for the entire week with minimal human (manual) intervention.
- Apart from the engineering side of the project, this project had an equal emphasis on how to market the product if a start-up were to develop it. This gave us new insights into studying the marketing world, and the important techniques used to develop a marketing plan.
- Core skills learned: develop and maintain a business model canvas, proper STP analysis of the product, and develop a marketing mix for the product.

LANGUAGES

Assamese	Native Language
English	Full Working Proficiency
Hindi	Bilingual Proficiency
French	Novice